Evan Beck

Milford, PA 18337 | 570-228-9807 | evandrydenbeck@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Background in Sales and Account Management, particularly in the education sector. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management. Ability to communicate between technical team and client. Love for computers and building new hardware.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, HTML5, CSS, Adobe Suite, Microsoft Suite

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

/white-label-forum - Github | Demo

A decentralized, private forum for communities to capture more personal conversations.

• Built and scaled clean and professional custom front-end using React and CSS, with UI in mind at every step • Utilized Rails to build relational database to best enhance user-experience and interactivity between users

Movie Reviews - Github | Demo

A public movie review website where users can interact with a large library of movies.

- Built front-end using React and CSS, with use of several components
- Single-Page Application, use of React Router to provide users many seamless features

EXPERIENCE

EDUCATION FIRST EXPLORE AMERICA Cambridge, MA Travel Consultant / Sales Associate 10/2019 - 07/2021 ◆ Consulted one-on-one across a year-long cycle with educators interested in showing their students the world. Built customized tours from a diverse portfolio of options.

• Managed portfolio of 20+ groups, over 200 middle-school aged students, responsible for revenue of \$400,000 across one-year period, amidst global pandemic.

BEST BUY, PACIFIC KITCHEN & HOME Watertown, MA Sales Consultant 03/2019 - 07/2019

- Provided retail customer service expertise and sales on hundreds of major appliance offerings, services, and promotions.
- Responsible for \$150,000 plus in revenue across a four-month period.

EVANS CONSOLES Milford, PA - Greater New York City Sales Associate / Project Manager 07/2017 - 07/2018 ● Provided sales and project management support for mission-critical control room projects.

EDUCATION ADVISORY BOARD Washington, DC Account Management Associate 07/2016 - 06/2017

- Acquired and strengthened relationships with over 200 client educational institutions by managing multi-level details across EAB teams to deliver best-practice campaigns for student success.
- Consistently met and exceeded quotas and goals, such as high renewal rates and event recruitment.

MAJOR CLARITY Milford, PA Co-Founder / Advisor, Head of Marketing & Growth 12/2013 - 12/2015

• Co-founded and built an online platform that delivers immersive 'real world' experiences for students to explore specific disciplines for their higher-education and career paths prior to investing valuable time and money into a firm direction.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 01/2022 - 04/2022

Roger Williams University Bristol, RI Bachelor of Science | Major: Business Marketing | Minor: Psychology | GPA: 3.2